Finding Aid for the United States Ephemera Collection LSC.0609
UCLA Library Special Collections
United States Ephemera collection
circa 1800
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0609
58.5 Linear Feet (118 boxes and 1 oversize folder)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942339093606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of broadsides, clippings, brochures and other ephemeral material relating to the U.S., except for material on California and of the Southwest, which are in two separate collections. Subjects include Alaska, William Cullen Bryant, Richard Henry Dana, Eugene V. Debs, dime novels, Mary Baker Eddy, William Faulkner, Freemasons, Jesse James, Martin Luther King, Mexicans in the US, National Wildlife Foundation, and John Greenleaf Whittier.
Organization and Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Ephemera -- United States.
- Abbey, Edward, 1927- (Box 1)
- Abbott, John Stevens Cabot, 1805-1877. (Box 1)
- Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922. (Box 1)
- Academic costume. (Box 1)
- Acoma Pueblo, NM (Box 1)
- Adachi, Kinnosuké. (Box 1)
- Adamana, Arizona. (Box 1)
- Adams, Abigail (Smith), 1744-1818. (Box 1)
- Adams, Alva, 1850-1922. (Box 1)
- Adams, Charles Francis, 1807-1886. (Box 1)
- Adams, Charles Frederick, 1851 - (Box 1)
- Adams, Charles Kendall, 1835-1902. (Box 1)
- Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. (Box 1)
- Adams, Samuel, 1722-1803. (Box 1)
- Adamson, William Charles, 1854-1929. (Box 1)
- Addams, Jane, 1860-1935. (Box 1)
- Ade, George, 1866-1944. (Box 1)
- Adler, Felix, 1851-1933. (Box 1)
- Advertising. (Box 1)
- Agassiz, Jean Louis Rodolphe, 1807-1873. (Box 1)
- Agee, James, 1909-1953. (Box 1)
- Agnew, David Haynes, 1818-1892. (Box 1)
- Agricultural museums. (Box 1)
- Agriculture-U.S. (Box 1)
- Aids Memorial Quilt (Box 1)
- Aiken, Conrad Potter, 1889 - (Box 1)
- Airlines., [2 folders.] (Box 1)
- Alaska., [2 folders.] (Box 101)
- Albuquerque, N.M. (Box 2)
- Alcoholism. (Box 2)
- Alcott, Louisa May, 1832-1888. (Box 2)
- Alcott, William Andrus, 1798-1859. (Box 2)
- Aldrich, Thomas Bailey, 1836-1907. (Box 2)
- Alger, Russell Alexander, 1836-1907. (Box 2)
- Aliens-legal status-U.S. (Box 117)
- Allen, Ethan, 1737-1789. (Box 2)
- Allen, Thomas, 1813-1882. (Box 2)
- Allison, William Boyd, 1829-1908 (Box 2)
- Allston, Washington, 1779-1843. (Box 2)
- Almanacs. (Box 2)
- Altgeld, John Peter, 1847-1902. (Box 2)
- Amendments, Equal Rights. (Box 2)
- American Alliance for Health, Physical Education, Recreation and Dance. Reston, Virginia. (Box 117)
- American Alpine Club., [3 folders.] (Box 2)
- American Antiquarian Society. (Box 2)
- American Association for State and Local History. (Box 2)
- American Library Association. (Box 2)
- American National Red Cross. (Box 101)
- American Revolution Bicentennial, 1776-1976., [2 folders.] (Box 101)
- American Society of Music Arrangers. (Box 3)
- Amerige, Annette J. (Box 3)
- Amerige, George H. (Box 3)
- Ames, Fisher, 1758-1808. (Box 3)
- Ames, Mary Clemmer, 1839-1884. (Box 3)
- Ames, Winthrop, 1871-1937. (Box 3)
- Anderson, George Everett, 1869-1940. (Box 3)
- Anderson, Robert, 1805-1871. (Box 3)
- Andrew, John Albion, 1818-1867. (Box 3)
- Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916. (Box 3)
- Anthony, Henry Bowen, 1815-1884. (Box 3)
- Anthony, Susan Brownell, 1820-1906. (Box 3)
- Architecture-conservation and restoration. (Box 3)
- Architecture-domestic. (Box 3)
- Arizona-history. (Box 102)
- Arizona Territorial Fair, Phoenix, Arizona, 1905. (Box 102)
- Arizona., [5 folders.] (Box 75)
- Arkansas. (Box 3)
- Armour, Philip Danforth, 1832-1901. (Box 3)
- Armstrong, William Jackson, 1841 - (Box 3)
- Arnold, Benedict, 1741-1801. (Box 3)
- Arnold, Henry Harley, 1886-1950. (Box 3)
- Art-museums and galleries. (Box 117)
- Art-museums. (Box 3)
- Ashe, John Baptista, 1748-1802. (Box 3)
- Ashurst, Henry Fountain, 1874 - (Box 3)
- Aspen, Colorado. (Box 3)
- Association of Research Libraries. (Box Unknown container 224 for instance of Association of Research Libraries.)
- Astor family. (Box 3)
- Atkinson, Edward, 1827-1905. (Box 3)
- Atlantic and Pacific Telegraph Company. (Box 3)
- Auer, Leopold, 1845-1930. (Box 3)
- Auld, Daniel. (Box 3)
- Authors League of America. (Box 3)
- Automobiles. (Box 3)
- Baker, Alexina F. (Box 3)
- Baker, Edward Dickinson, 1811-1861. (Box 3)
- Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937. (Box 3)
- Ballou, Hosea, 1771-1852. (Box 4)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1893. (Box 4)
- Bankhead, William Brockman, 1874-1940. (Box 4)
- Banks and banking-United States. (Box 4)
- Banks, Nathaniel Prentiss, 1816-1894. (Box 4)
- Banning, Phineas, 1830-1885. (Box 4)
- Barnard, Frederick Augustus Porter, 1809-1889. (Box 4)
- Barnes, Djuna, 1892-1982. (Box 4)
- Barnett, C.C. (Box 4)
- Barney, Natalie Clifford. (Box 4)
- Barnum, Phineas Taylor, 1810-1891. (Box 4)
- Barwise, Joseph Hudson, 1868-1941. (Box 4)
- Bates, Katharine Lee, 1859-1929. (Box 4)
- Bauer, Harold, 1873-1951. (Box 4)
- Bayard, Thomas Francis, 1828-1898. (Box 4)
- Beard, Daniel Carter, 1850-1941. (Box 4)
- Beauregard, Pierre Gustave Toutant, 1818-1893. (Box 4)
- Beecher family. (Box 4)
- Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887. (Box 4)
- Beecher, John, 1904 - (Box 4)
- Bell, Alexander Graham, 1847-1922. (Box 4)
- Bellowd, Henry Whitney, 1814-1882. (Box 4)
- Bellows, E.C., d. 1829. (Box 4)
- Bemelmans, Ludwig, 1898-1962. (Box 4)
- Benchley, Robert Charles, 1889-1945. (Box 4)
- Benjamin, Park, 1809-1864. (Box 4)
- Benson, William Shepherd, 1855-1932. (Box 4)
- Benton, Thomas Hart, 1782-1858. (Box 4)
- Berkman, Alexander, 1870-1936. (Box 4)
- Berry, Albert Seaton, 1836-1908. (Box 5)
- Best, Philip, 1814-1869. (Box 5)
- Bethune, Thomas Green, 1849-1908. (Box 5)
- Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927. (Box 5)
- Bevier, Isabel, 1860-1942. (Box 5)
- Bibliographical Society of America (The). (Box 5)
- Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1944. (Box 5)
- Bierce, Ambrose, 1942-1914? (Box 5)
- Bigelow, Poultney, 1855 - (Box 5)
- Birch, Reginald Bathurst, 1856-1943. (Box 5)
- Bisbee, Arizona. (Box 5)
- Black History Month (Box 5)
- Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893. (Box 5)
- Blair, Francis Preston, 1791-1876. (Box 5)
- Blanck, Jacob Nathaniel, 1906-1974. (Box 5)
- Bliss, Cornelius Newton, 1833-1911. (Box 5)
- Bobock, Thomas S., 1815-1891. (Box 5)
- Boker, George Henry, 1823-1890. (Box 5)
- Bolton, Henry Carrington, 1843-1903. (Box 5)
- Bonaparte, Charles Joseph, 1851-1921. (Box 5)
- Bond, Carrie Jacobs, 1862-1946. (Box 5)
- Boni & Liveright, firm, publishers, New York. (Box 5)
- Bonner, Robert, 1824-1899. (Box 5)
- Bonney, Charles Carroll, 1831-1903. (Box 5)
- Bonney, William H. (Box 5)
- Bonus Expeditionary Force, 1932. (Box 5)
- Book thefts. (Box 5)
- Books-prospectuses (Box 5)
  General note
  Missing 9/2003.
- Booksellers and bookselling. (Box 117)
- Boone, Daniel, 1735-1820. (Box 5)
- Boston. (Box 102)
- Bottles-collectors and collecting. (Box 117)
- Boucicault, Dion George, 1856-1929. (Box 6)
- Bourke-White, Margaret, 1906-1971. (Box Unknown container 225 for instance of Bourke-White, Margaret, 1906-1971.)
  Missing, 9/1991.
- Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905. (Box 6)
- Bowles, Paul Frederic, 1911 - (Box 6)
- Bowles, Samuel, 1826-1878. (Box 6)
- Boyesen, Hjalmar Hjorth, 1848-1895. (Box 6)
- Bradish, Luther, 1783-1863. (Box 6)
- Brainard, Joe, 1942 - (Box 6)
- Bremer, Frederika, 1801-1865. (Box 6)
- Brent, Henry Johnson, 1811-1880. (Box 6)
- Briggs, George Nixon, 1796-1861. (Box 6)
- Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1836-1899. (Box 6)
- Brisbane, Arthur, 1864-1936. (Box 6)
- Broadsides, American. (Box 6)
- Bromfield, Louis, 1896-1956. (Box 6)
- Brooklyn. (Box 6)
- Brooks, Erastus, 1815-1886. (Box 6)
- Brooks, John Graham, 1846-1938. (Box 6)
- Brooks, Noah, 1830-1903. (Box 6)
- Brooks, Peter Chardon, 1767-1849. (Box 6)
- Brooks, Phillips, 1835-1893. (Box 6)
- Broun, Heywood Campbell, 1888-1939. (Box 6)
- Brown, Charles Brockden, 1771-1810. (Box 6)
- Brown, George H. (Box 6)
- Brown, Goold, 1791-1857. (Box 6)
- Brown, John, 1722-1787. (Box 6)
- Brown, John, 1800-1859. (Box 6)
- Browne, Charles Farrar, 1834-1867. (Box 6)
- Browne, John Ross, 1821-1875. (Box 6)
- Browne, Lewis, 1897-1949. (Box 6)
- Brownlow, William Gannaway, 1805-1877. (Box 6)
- Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925., [3 folders.] (Box 6)
- Bryant, William Cullen, 1794-1878. (Box 102)
- Bryce Canyon National Park. (Box 7)
- Buchwald, Art, 1925 - (Box 7)
- Buck, Pearl (Sydenstricker), 1892-1973. (Box 7)
- Buckley, James Munroe, 1836-1920. (Box 7)
- Buckner, Walker, 1871-1939. (Box 7)
- Buell, Don Carlos, 1818-1898. (Box 7)
- Buffalo, New York. (Box 127)
- Bühlig, Richard, 1880-1952. (Box 7)
- Burch, Henry Kenyon, 1873-1957. (Box 7)
- Burgess, Gelett, 1866-1951. (Box 7)
- Burke, Stevenson, 1824-1904. (Box 7)
- Burleson, Albert Sidney, 1863-1937. (Box 7)
- Burnett, Frances Hodgson, 1849-1924. (Box 7)
- Burns, William John, 1861-1924. (Box 7)
- Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 1824-1881. (Box 7)
- Burroughs, Edgar Rice, 1875-1950. (Box 7)
- Burroughs, John, 1837-1921. (Box 7)
- Burton, Robert, 1747-1825. (Box 7)
- Business enterprises-U.S. (Box 7)
- Butler, Benjamin Franklin, 1818-1893. (Box 7)
- Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947. (Box 7)
- Butterfield Overland Mail. (Box 7)
- Bynner, Witter, 1881-1968. (Box 7)
- Byrd, Harry Flood, 1887 - (Box 7)
- Cabell, James Branch, 1879-1958. (Box 7)
- Cable, George Washington, 1844-1925. (Box 7)
- Cage, John, 1912 - (Box 7)
- Calendars. (Box 117)
- Calhoun, John Caldwell, 1782-1850. (Box 7)
- Calvin, Ross, 1889-1970. (Box 102)
- Camp Fire Girls Inc. (The). (Box 102)
- Camp Wadsworth, S.C. (Box 103)
- Campbell, James Edwin, 1843-1924. (Box 8)
- Cancer. (Box 8)
- Cannon, John L. (Box 8)
- Cannon, Joseph Gurney, 1836-1929. (Box 8)
- Canyon de Chelley National Monument. (Box 8)
- Cape Cod, Mass. (Box 8)
- Caraway, Thaddeus H., 1871-1931. (Box 8)
- Carleton, Will, 1845-1912. (Box 8)
- Carlisle, John Griffin, 1835-1910. (Box 8)
- Carlsbad Caverns, N.M. (Box 8)
- Carman, William Bliss, 1861-1929. (Box 8)
- Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919. (Box 8)
- Carson, Christopher, 1809-1868. (Box 8)
- Carter, Jimmy, 1924 - (Box 8)
- Carus, Paul, 1852-1919. (Box 8)
- Carver, Raymond. (Box 8)
- Cary, Alice, 1920-1871. (Box 8)
- Cary, William Paxton, 1882-1943. (Box 8)
- Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866. (Box 8)
- Cather, Willa Sibert, 1873-1947. (Box 8)
- Catt, Carrie (Lane) Chapman, 1859-1947. (Box 103)
- Cattell, James McKean, 1860-1944. (Box 103)
- Cattle brands-Texas. (Box 103)
- Cattle brands-The West. (Box Unknown container 226 for instance of Cattle brands-The West.)
- Cemeteries. (Box 103)
- Censorship-U.S. (Box 9)
- Censorship-U.S. (Box 119)
- Center for Creative Photography., [2 folders.] (Box 9)
- Chadwick, John White, 1940 -1904. (Box 9)
- Chaffee, Adna Romanza, 1842-1914. (Box 9)
- Chamberlain, Ebenezer Mattoon, 1805-1861. (Box 9)
- Chamberlain, George Earle, 1854-1928. (Box 9)
- Chandler, William Eaton, 1835-1917. (Box 9)
- Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842. (Box 9)
- Chapin, Edwin Hubbell, 1814-1880. (Box 9)
- Chaplin, Ralph Hosea, 1887-1961. (Box 9)
- Chapman, Charles Clarke, 1853 - (Box 9)
- Charities-U.S. (Box 9)
- Chase, Salmon Portland, 1813-1873. (Box 9)
- Chase, William Merritt, 1849-1916. (Box 9)
- Chauncy, Charles, 1592-1672. (Box 9)
- Cheney, Horace B. (Box 9)
- Chicago-Fire, 1871. (Box 9)
- Chicago, Ill. (Box 9)
- Children's Defense Fund. (Box 76)
- Children's literature., [3 folders.] (Box 76)
- Childs, George William, 1829-1894. (Box 9)
- Childs, Samuel Shannon, 1863-1925. (Box 9)
- China-diplomatic and consular service-U.S. (Box 9)
- Chinese in the U.S. (Box 103)
- Choate, Rufus, 1799-1859. (Box 103)
- Church, Frederick Stuart, 1842-1924. (Box 103)
- Cigarette cards. (Box 103)
- Circus., [2 folders.] (Box 103)
- Civil defense. (Box 103)
- Claiborne, William Charles Coles, 1775-1817. (Box 10)
- Clark, Horace Francis, 1815-1873. (Box 10)
- Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. (Box 10)
- Clarke, S.J. (Box 10)
- Clay, Cassius Marcellus, 1810-1903. (Box 10)
- Clay, Henry, 1777-1852. (Box 10)
- Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910., [4 folders.] (Box 10)
- Cleveland, Ohio. (Box 127)
- Cleveland, Orestes, 1829-1896. (Box 10)
- Clinton, De Witt, 1769-1828. (Box 10)
- Cobb, Irving Shrewsbury, 1876-1944. (Box 10)
- Coburn, Foster Dwight, 1846-1924. (Box 11)
- Cochise County, Arizona. (Box 11)
- Cody, William Frederick, 1846-1917. (Box 11)
- Coleman, L.J. (Box 11)
- Colfax, Schuyler, 1823-1885. (Box 11)
- Collier, John, 1884 - (Box 11)
- Collyer, Robert, 1823-1912. (Box 11)
- Color photography. (Box 11)
- Colorado., [3 folders.] (Box 11)
- Columbia River. (Box Unknown container 227 for instance of Columbia River.)
- Columbia University.
  Missing 7/18/2007.
- Columbia University., [3 folders.] (Box 116)
- Columbus Quincentenary, 1992-1993. (Box 118)
- Conkling, Roscoe, 1829-1888. (Box 103)
- Connecticut. (Box 103)
- Consumer protection. (Box 104)
- Converse, Myron F. (Box 104)
- Cook, Edmund Vance, 1866-1932. (Box 104)
- Cookbooks. (Box 12)
- Cooke, Josiah Parsons, 1827-1894. (Box 12)
- Cooke, Rose Terry, 1827-1892. (Box 12)
- Coolidge, Asenath Carver. (Box 12)
- Coombs, Leslie. (Box 12)
- Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art, New York. (Box 12)
- Cooper, James Fenimore, 1789-1851. (Box 12)
- Cooper, Peter, 1791-1883. (Box 12)
- Cope, Edward Drinker, 1840-1897. (Box 12)
- Copeland, Royal Samuel, 1868-1938. (Box 12)
- Corbett, Henry Winslow, 1827-1903. (Box 12)
- Corcoran, Michael, 1827-1863. (Box 12)
- Corinth, Miss., Battle of, 1862. (Box Unknown container 228 for instance of Corinth, Miss., Battle of, 1862.)
- Cornell University. (Box 12)
- Cornwell, Deam, 1892-1960. (Box 12)
- Corwin, Thomas, 1794-1865. (Box 12)
- Courtenay, William Ashmead, 1831-1908. (Box 12)
- Cowboys. (Box 12)
- Cox, Jacob Dodson, 1828-1900. (Box 12)
- Cox, Palmer, 1840-1924. (Box 104)
- Cox, Samuel Sullivan, 1824-1889. (Box 12)
- Crane, Frank, 1861-1928. (Box 12)
- Crane, Stephen, 1871-1900. (Box 12)
- Crapsey, Algernon Sidney, 1847-1927. (Box 12)
- Crater Lake National Park. (Box 12)
- Crawford, William Harris, 1772-1834. (Box 12)
- Creeley, Robnert, 1926 - (Box 12)
- Crittenden, John Jordan, 1787-1863. (Box 12)
- Crooker, Joseph Henry, 1850-1931. (Box 12)
- Crosby, Caresse, 1892-1970. (Box 12)
- Crosby, Ernest Howard, 1856-1907. (Box 12)
- Crosby, Howard, 1826-1891. (Box 12)
- Crosby, John Sherwin. (Box 12)
- Cummings, Edward Estlin, 1894 - (Box 104)
- Cummins, Albert Baird, 1850-1926. (Box 12)
- Curtis, Charles, 1860-1936. (Box 12)
- Curtis, George William, 1824-1892. (Box 12)
- Da Costa, Jacob Mendez, 1833-1900. (Box 12)
- Dahlberg, Edward, 1900 - (Box 12)
- Dana, Charles Anderson, 1819-1897. (Box 12)
- Dana, Richard Henry, 1815-1882. (Box 104)
- Dancing-Folk and national dances. (Box 13)
- Dancing., [2 folders.] (Box 13)
- Dandridge, Mrs. Danske (Bedinger), 1858 - (Box 13)
- Dane, Henry Craige. (Box 13)
- Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948. (Box 13)
- Dartmouth College. (Box 13)
- Daughters of the American Revolution. (Box 117)
- Davie, William Richardson, 1756-1820. (Box 13)
- Davis, David, 1815-1886. (Box 13)
- Davis, Jefferson Colombus, 1828-1879. (Box 13)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. (Box 13)
- Davis, John 1787-1854. (Box 13)
- Davis, Richard Harding, 1864-1916. (Box 13)
- Dawson, Fielding. (Box 13)
- Day, Jeremiah, 1773-1867. (Box 13)
- Dealey, George Bannerman, 1859-1946. (Box 13)
- Dearborn, Henry, 1751-1829. (Box 13)
- Debs, Eugene Victor, 1855-1926. (Box 104)
- Decatur, Stephen, 1751-1808. (Box 14)
- Deems, Charles Force, 1820-1893. (Box 14)
- Delaware. (Box 14)
- Demkpsey, Edward J. (Box 14)
- Democratic Party., [5 folders.] (Box 78)
- Democratic Party. Prior to 1964., [5 folders.] (Box 77)
- Democratic Party. (Box 78)
- Denver, Colorado. (Box 14)
- Denver, James William, 1817-1892. (Box 14)
- Depew, Chauncey Mitchell, 1834-1928. (Box 14)
- Detective and mystery stories-bibliography-catalogs. (Box 14)
- Devos, Julius Emil, 1848-1937. (Box 14)
- Dewey, George, 1837-1917. (Box 14)
- Dewey, John, 1859-1952. (Box 14)
- Dickinson, Anna Elizabeth, 1842-1932. (Box 14)
- Dime novels. (Box 104)
- Disney World. Orlando, Florida. (Box 117)
- Dix, John Adams, 1798-1879. (Box 15)
- Dixon, Samuel Orbison, 1851-1918. (Box 15)
- Doak, William Nuckles, 1882-1933. (Box 15)
- Dobie, James Frank, 1888-1964. (Box 121)
- Dobie, James Frank, 1888-1964., [4 folders.] (Box 79)
- Dodge, Mary Mapes, 1851-1905. (Box 15)
- Dole, Sanford Ballard, 1844-1926. (Box 15)
- Donnelly, Ignatius, 1831-1901. (Box 15)
- Doris Humphrey Society. (Box 15)
- Douglas, Arizona. (Box 15)
- Douglas, George William, 1863-1945 (Box 15)
- Douglas, Stephen Arnold, 1813-1861. (Box 15)
- Douglas, William Lewis, 1845-1924. (Box 15)
- Dow, Neal, 1804-1897. (Box 15)
- Draper Company. Hopedale, Mass. (Box 105)
- Dreier, Theodore, 1871-1945. (Box 15)
- Dreier, Thomas, 1884 - (Box 15)
- Drug abuse-study and teaching. (Box 15)
- Du Pont, Henry Algernon, 1838-1926. (Box 15)
- Duncan, Isadora, 1878-1927. (Box 15)
- Dunne, Edward Fitzsimons, 1853-1937. (Box 15)
- Dupont, Thomas Coleman, 1863-1930. (Box 15)
- Durant, William James, 1885 - (Box 15)
- Dwight, Timothy, 1752-1817. (Box 15)
- Eastman, Max, 1883 - (Box 15)
- Ecology. (Box 105)
- Eddy, Mary (Baker), 1821-1910. (Box 15)
- Edgar, William F. (Box 16)
- Edge, Walter Evans, 1874 - (Box 16)
- Edison, Thomas Alva, 1847-1931., [2 folders.] (Box 16)
- Edmonds, John Worth, 1799-1874. (Box 16)
- Education-U.S., [2 folders.] (Box 16)
- Eells, James, d. 1886. (Box 16)
- Eggleston, George Cary, 1839-1911. (Box 16)
- Egocentrics and eccentricities., [4 folders.] (Box 80)
- Egocentrics and eccentricities. (Box 121)
- Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955. (Box 16)
- El Paso, Texas. (Box 105)
- Elder, William Henry, 1819-1904. (Box 16)
- Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926. (Box 16)
- Ellis, Arthur MacDonald, 1875-1932. (Box 105)
- Elllroy, James, 1948 - (Box 105)
- Ely, Richard Theodore, 1854-1943. (Box 17)
- Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882., [3 folders.] (Box 17)
- Endecott, John, 1589?-1665. (Box 17)
- English, Thomas Dunn, 1819-1902. (Box 17)
- Entertainers, Afro-American. (Box 17)
- Errett, Isaac, 1820-1888. (Box 17)
- Erskine, John, 1897-1951. (Box 17)
- Eseverri, Dolores S. (Box 17)
- Eugene, Oregon. (Box 17)
- Evans, Robley Dunglison, 1846-1912. (Box 17)
- Evarts, William Maxwell, 1818-1901. (Box 17)
- Everett, Edward, 1794-1865. (Box 17)
- Ewing, Thomas, 1789-1871. (Box 17)
- Expositions. (Box 117)
- Fairbanks, Charles Warren, 1852-1918. (Box 17)
- Fairman, James, 1825-1904. (Box 17)
- Fallout shelters. (Box 17)
- Fanning, David, 1755?-1825. (Box 17)
- Fanning, Edmund, 1737-1818. (Box 17)
- Farley, James Aloysius, 1888 - (Box 17)
- Farragut, David Glascow, 1801-1870. (Box 105)
- Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979. (Box 105)
- Fashion-U.S. (Box 117)
- Fast food restaurants. (Box 105)
- Faulkner, William, 1897-1962., [2 folders.] (Box 18)
- Faulkner, William, 1897-1962. (Box 18)
- Faust, Frederick, 1892-1944. (Box 18)
- Favary, Ethelbert. (Box 18)
- Fawcett, Edgar, 1847-1904. (Box 18)
- Fels, Joseph, 1854-1914. (Box 18)
- Fenton, Reuben Eaton, 1819-1885. (Box 18)
- Ferguson, Charles, 1863 - (Box 18)
- Ferguson, Samuel L. (Box 18)
- Ferguson, William Porter Frisbee, 1861-1929. (Box 18)
- Fergusson, Erna, 1888-1964. (Box 18)
- Fergusson, Harvey, 1890-1971. (Box 18)
- Ferrell, A.W. (Box 18)
- Ferrell, John. (Box 18)
- Fessenden, Reginald Aubrey, 1866-1932. (Box 18)
- Fessenden, William Pitt, 1806-1869. (Box 18)
- Field, Eugene, 1850-1895. (Box 18)
- Field, Henry Martyn, 1822-1907. (Box 18)
- Field, Marshall, 1834-1906. (Box 18)
- Field, Mary Katherine Keemle, 1838-1896. (Box 18)
- Fields, James Thomas, 1817-1881. (Box 18)
- Fish, Stuyvesant, 1851-1923. (Box 18)
- Fisher, Albert Kendrick, 1856-1948. (Box 105)
- Fisher, George Park, 1827-1909. (Box 105)
- Fisher, Harrison, 1877-1934. (Box 105)
- Fisher, Vardis, 1895 - (Box 105)
- Fisher, Walter Lowrie, 1862-1935. (Box 105)
- Fishing industry-U.S. (Box 117)
- Fisk, Wilbur, 1792-1839. (Box 105)
- Fitch, Asa, 1809-1879. (Box 105)
- Flags., [5 folders.] (Box 81)
- Flanner, Janet, 1892 - (Box 105)
- Flint, Austin, 1836 - (Box 105)
- Floods. (Box 105)
- Florida. (Box 19)
- Flower, Benjamin Orange, 1858-1918. (Box 19)
- Flowers-Western U.S. (Box 112)
  Not in box, 11/1/2007.
- Folk, Joseph Wingate, 1869-1923. (Box 19)
- Folklore, American. (Box 19)
- Foote, Andrew Hull, 1806-1863. (Box 19)
- Foraker, Joseph Benson, 1846-1917. (Box 19)
- Ford Motor Company. (Box 19)
- Ford, Carydon L. (Box 19)
- Ford, Henry, 1863-1947. (Box 19)
- Forney, John Wien, 1817-1881. (Box 19)
- Forres, Lewis E. (Box 19)
- Forsyth, John, 1780-1841. (Box 19)
- Forsyth, John, 1780-1841. (Box 10)
- Fort Bridger, Wyoming. (Box 19)
- Fort Ticonderoga, N.Y. (Box 19)
- Fort Union, Montana. (Box 19)
- Foss, Cyrus David, 1834-1910. (Box 19)
- Foster, Charles, 1828-1904. (Box 19)
- Foy, Samuel Calvert. (Box 19)
- Francis, John Wakefield, 1789-1861. (Box 19)
- Francis, Vida Hunt, 1870-1957. (Box 19)
- Frank, Glenn, 1887-1940. (Box 19)
- Frank, Henry, 1854-1933. (Box 19)
- Frankfurter, Felix, 1882 - (Box 19)
- Franklin Mint. Pennsylvania., [4 folders.] (Box 82)
- Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790. (Box 105)
- Fraternal societies-U.S. (Box 19)
- Fredericksburg, Va. (Box 19)
- Freeman, Daniel, 1837 - (Box Unknown container 229 for instance of Freeman, Daniel, 1837 -)
- Freemasons. Missouri., [2 folders.] (Box 20)
- Freemasons. New York. (Box 20)
- Freemasons. Virginia. (Box 20)
- Freemasons. Wisconsin. (Box 20)
- Frelinghuysen, Frederick Theodore, 1817-1885. (Box 20)
- French, Alice, 1850-1934. (Box 20)
- French-American Chamber of Commerce. (Box 20)
- Frick, Henry Clay, 1949-1919. (Box 20)
- Frontier and pioneer life-The West. (Box 20)
- Frost, Robert, 1875-1963. (Box 20)
- Frothingham, George Edward, 1836 - (Box 20)
- Fuller, Edward Hawley Laton, 1851-1909. (Box 20)
- Fulton, Robert, 1765-1815. (Box 20)
- Funk, Isaac Kaufman, 1839-1912. (Box 20)
- Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912. (Box 20)
- Furness, William Henry, 1802-1896. (Box 20)
- Gale, Zona, 1874-1938. (Box 20)
- Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849. (Box 20)
- Gallinger, Jacob Harold, 1837-19. (Box 20)
- Galveston, Texas. (Box 106)
- Games. (Box 106)
- Gardener, Helen Hamilton, 1853-1925. (Box 106)
- Gardner, Erle Stanley, 1889-1970. (Box 21)
- Garfield, Harry Augustus, 1863-1942. (Box 21)
- Garfield, James Rudolph, 1865 - (Box 21)
- Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940. (Box 21)
- Garr, James N. (Box 21)
- Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879. (Box 21)
- Gates, Cassius E. (Box 21)
- Gates, George Augustus, 1851-1912. (Box 21)
- Gaynor, William Jay, 1849-1913. (Box 21)
- Geismar, Maxwell David, 1909 - (Box 21)
- George, Henry, 1839-1897. (Box 21)
- George, Henry, 1862-1916. (Box 21)
- Georgia. (Box 21)
- Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. (Box 21)
- Gettysburg National Military Park. (Box 21)
- Gibbons, Floyd Phillips, 1887-1938. (Box 21)
- Gibbons, James, Cardinal, 1834-1921. (Box 106)
- Gibson, Charles Dana, 1867 - (Box 106)
- Gibson, Hugh Simons, 1883-1954. (Box 106)
- Gibson, Ralph, 1939 - (Box 106)
- Gibson, William Hamilton, 1850-1896. (Box 106)
- Gilbert, Anne (Hartley), 1821-1904. (Box 106)
- Gilbert, Grove Karl, 1843-1918. (Box 106)
- Gilder, Richard Watson, 1844-1909. (Box 106)
- Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908. (Box 106)
- Ginsberg, Allen, 1926 - (Box 106)
- Glacier National Park. (Box 106)
- Gladden, Washington, 1836-1918. (Box 106)
- Glaser, Al. (Box 22)
- Glasgow, Ellen Anderson Gholson, 1874-1945. (Box 22)
- Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940. (Box 22)
- Goldwater, Barry Morris, 1909 - (Box 22)
- Gompers, Samuel, 1850-1924. (Box 22)
- Goossens, Eugene, 1893 - (Box 22)
- Goudy, Frederick William, 1865-1947. (Box 22)
- Gould, George Milbry, 1848-1922. (Box 22)
- Graham, George Rex, 1813-1894. (Box 22)
- Grand Army of the Republic. (Box 22)
- Grand Canyon National Park, Arizona. (Box 106)